Max Caudle

Data Scientist

Personal Info

Address

4490 Driftwood Pl. Boulder, CO 80301

Phone

804-387-2413

E-mail

maxwell.caudle@gmail.com

Personal Website

http://www.maxcaudle.com

GitHub

https://github.com/MasonCaiby

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/maxcaudle

Technical Skills

Excel and VBA

Expert

Python

Advanced

SQL

Advanced

Machine Learning

Advanced

Statistics

Advanced

Intermediate

Soft Skills

Problem Solving

Expert

Critical Thinking

Expert

Communication

Expert

Data Scientist with 7 years experience analyzing data, managing projects, implementing improved processes, designing and developing automation tools. Experienced in computer vision, natural language processing, and algorithm development. Achievements include reducing reporting time from 3 weeks to 4 days, improving report accuracy from 50% to 95%, and continual recognition as one of the most efficient workers at and well beyond job description.

- Took initiative and worked independently to create a report validation, submittal, and communication tool that stopped threatened lawsuits, increased report accuracy, and dropped reporting time and technical knowledge requirements
- · Created multiple models and tools, focused on business growth and improvement
- Highest number of closed cases, company wide, over a rolling year, in 9 months
- · Lead multiple quantitative analyses project groups, wrote and presented reports on our findings
- Managed academic and solar installation teams and projects

Experience

2018-02 -

present

Data Science Projects

- Radar Data (Boulder AI) contracted to improve code, model, and convert Keras code to an old version of Tensorflow improved accuracy from 86% to over 90%
- IR data (Boulder AI) Built a model to find "red zones" using IR and Depth Data
- Wildlife Detection (Boulder AI) on a Colorado Parks & Wildlife study of wilderness restoration's effectiveness. Built a wildlife detection model with TensorFlow that obtained a precision of 83%. Included a robust pipeline to allow future training of the model for classification.
- SO Handler- Keras Recurrent Neural Net that produces Terry Pratchett text.
 Pulls unique images from Flickr every day and combines them with some generated Pratchett text in a daily email.
- Picnic Table- A hand made picnic table with a Raspberry Pi running 2 LED strips controllable from a website.
- Auto App- A bot that applies to jobs on AngelList with customized cover letters

2017-03 -

Agency Reporting Associate

present

- Analyzed and reported energy data to 13 nationwide incentive agencies
- Used Excel and VBA to create tools that ensure data integrity, automate tasks, and streamline processes- decreasing the time to file reports by over 50%
- Reduced average response time from 1 week to 1 day, caseload from 70 to 30
- Discovered and helped resolve multiple issues in our reporting software
- Became the companies saving grace for many customers, through excellent response time and service

2016-02 -

Co-Founder

AlsoEnergy

2017-03

Endless Electricity

- Co-founded and managed a solar subcontracting company; managed projects, finances, and installs
- Created a model that predicted solar cost, payback time, savings, and economic impact
- Project managed large residential installation (~50kW), with tight time constraints

Education

2018 -

Galvanize - Data Science

2018

Data Science Immersive that focuses on machine learning, automation, analysis, modeling, visualization, and data based decision making.

2011 -

B.A. Economics University of Colorado at Boulder

2015

Focused on, and excelled at quantitative analysis and actionable decisions, using R and Mathematica.

Led group projects in advanced calculus, statistics, and economics courses.